<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-07-10T15:54:00+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Renting a flat in Berlin</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/renting_a_flat_in_berlin/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/renting_a_flat_in_berlin/</id>
    <published>2015-07-10T15:54:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-10T17:08:20+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The idea of finding a place to live always fills me with mixed emotions. On the one hand there's the excitement of finding that great new flat. On the other hand you have to pack up all your stuff and lug it across town in the van you don't own. Then there's the competition. Oh, the competition. There will be lines…there &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be disappointment. But it will be worth it, because in Berlin, there is something out there for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at the below graphic. Pick two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pick Two" src="/images/picktwo-36d9b3ea.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can have a spacious, cheap apartment - but it won't be close to the action. You can get a cheap and central place, but you're going to have to share a studio. You get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; This is not gospel. There are plenty of exceptions to the rule. I know a guy that's still paying the same price he paid in the 90s for a 2 bedroom flat in Friedrichshain. I'd love to hear your stories in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-are-the-options"&gt;What are the options?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many different ways to go about getting a flat in Berlin. I'm going to list a few of the most common ones below and share my experience. Please, if you have anything to add, let me know!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="flatshare"&gt;Flatshare&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flatsharing in Berlin is one of the cheapest, easiest and most social ways to get accomodation. There are a heap of websites that you can search that display a whole heap of flatshares from short-term contracts to permanent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most ads will tell you the warm rent price, meaning bills are included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are a lot of flat shares in all areas of Berlin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The social aspect of moving in with new people&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flat shares are cheaper than living alone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your housemate/s may be f**king crazy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When one moves out, it becomes your responsibility to find another tenant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.wg-gesucht.de/en"&gt;http://www.wg-gesucht.de/en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/666822796665326"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/groups/666822796665326&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="get-your-own-place"&gt;Get your own place&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting your own rental contract is great. You have the freedom of living in your own house, making your own rules. If you want to leave the dishes out for a week at a time, you can (each to their own).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get your own contract, many landlords will want to see a SCHUFA credit check. You can get this online. They may also want proof of some of your last paychecks. If they choose you out of the &lt;strong&gt;many&lt;/strong&gt; people who walk through their flat, you'll have to give them a bond. This is usually 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They'll tell you the cold rent price. So make sure your budget allows for utilites. They may or may not include a kitchen in the price. Many tenants are expected to bring their own kitchen, so ask the question. You'll also need to furnish the place, so get ready to spend some serious money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The flat is yours - do what you want&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You're locked in for at least 12 months&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Privacy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It's expensive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The competition is fierce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unfurnished (most without kitchen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.wg-gesucht.de/en"&gt;http://www.wg-gesucht.de/en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.immobilienscout24.de/"&gt;http://www.immobilienscout24.de/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="airbnb"&gt;AirBnB&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I had determined my arrival date in Berlin, I also booked an AirBnB for 2 months. I figured two months would be enough time to explore the city and find out which area I wanted to move into long-term, along with the process it takes to get the flat in said area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AirBnB is great for a short term stay if you can find an affordable one. I chose a whole flat, told the host that I wanted it for two months and she knocked the price down for such a lengthy stay. In hindsight, this was actually the cheapest apartment we had (my housemate and I) at 700€ a month, including utilities and internet (and of course, it's furnished) in the heart of Neukölln.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Short term&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Furnished&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No bills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Short term&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It's going to be more expensive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.airbnb.com"&gt;http://www.airbnb.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="expat-rentals"&gt;Expat Rentals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was completely against expat rentals before coming to Berlin. In a strange twist of events, I now live in one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my AirBnB rental, I came across an expat rental company online and went to look at an apartment. It was big - really big, and it was a 9 minute tram to work in Mitte, a 15 minute walk down to Warschauer Str. and the bars in Friedrichshain. There were plenty of supermarkets nearby and there was one of the best parks in Berlin on our doorstep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was also furnished and all bills were included in the rental price of 900€ a month (between two of us). I could probably find a similarly sized house (2 bedroom, big kitchen, balcony) in the same street on my own contract for about 600€ a month - but I'd need to add utilities and internet on a monthly basis, and have a big initial layout for a kitchen, washing machine and all furniture. Who knew matresses were so damn expensive!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Short/medium/long-term&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Furnished&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bills included&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slightly more expensive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not that many apartments to choose from&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.xpatrentals.com/country/germany/berlin"&gt;https://www.xpatrentals.com/country/germany/berlin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.berlin99.com"&gt;http://www.berlin99.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.crocodilian.de/"&gt;https://www.crocodilian.de/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know how you got on with renting a place in Berlin. Are you renting at the same price you were when the Deutsche Mark was around? Let me know in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Getting a Job in Berlin</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/getting_a_job_in_berlin/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/getting_a_job_in_berlin/</id>
    <published>2015-07-10T11:18:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-10T13:21:39+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lets start by saying that this is no easy task. I overheard a conversation with two guys a while back - &lt;em&gt;Guy 1&lt;/em&gt; was a house-painter by trade. He was ready to work - would bring his van over from London, with all his brushes and rollers and make a life in Berlin. Simples. &lt;em&gt;Guy 2&lt;/em&gt; told him, in no uncertain terms, that for every one of him, there were 100 Polish house-painters who were willing to work longer, harder and for less money than he was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I don't know about Polish painters or their work ethic, but what I do know is that as an Australian in Berlin it's tough to find work. The figures speak for themselves. Currently unemployment in Berlin is at 10.8%. That's high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Unemployment in Berlin" src="/images/unemployment-67f97877.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="patience-is-a-virtue"&gt;Patience is a virtue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first piece of advice I can give you is to be patient. With unemployment so high, everybody is vying for the same jobs. You may not (I certainly hope you do!) fall into a job in the first week of getting your &lt;a href="../working_visa_in_germany/"&gt;Working Visa&lt;/a&gt;. It may even take a couple of &lt;em&gt;months&lt;/em&gt;. Be prepared. Bring enough money to survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="pick-the-right-industry"&gt;Pick the right industry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are jobs that are well suited to expats, travelers, backpackers and the like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm a 'Tech Professional', as it were. Berlin is the 'Silicon Valley of Europe' and so there were a lot of Tech positions in Startups that I had the opportunity of applying for. &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://berlinstartupjobs.com"&gt;Berlin Startup Jobs&lt;/a&gt; was a great resource for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are certain jobs that are really well suited to backpackers and travelers. They may not be what you do back at home, but if you're more about working to live in Berlin, then they might be perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tour Guide.&lt;/strong&gt; If you know a bit about history, look into running walking tours with a group like &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.neweuropetours.eu/work-with-us.html"&gt;Sandeman's&lt;/a&gt;. It's tip based, so you'll have good days and bad days, but from what I've worked out when participating on these tours - good days are very good. Summer is better, for obvious reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hostel Jobs.&lt;/strong&gt; This one is kind of obvious, but worth mentioning. Hostels are looking for expats to engage their customers. The job isnt glamourous - you'll clean toilets and make beds, but you might snag a free room, if you can hack living where you work. It also won't be very well paid, but you can survive Berlin on a budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bar Work.&lt;/strong&gt; This will be infinitely easier if you have a basic grasp of the German language, but there are plenty of bars and clubs around who will give you a job running glasses or mopping the floor. A lot of these places pay cash and the work may be sporadic - don't be disheartened if they let you go…it's not because you're shit at cleaning floors, when they can't afford you, they can't afford you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cafes/Restaurants.&lt;/strong&gt; There is an ever growing presence of English-speaking eateries in Berlin. A lot of these places don't cater to the German language whatsoever, so finding a job in an American burger joint for example, may be an option worth looking into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office Work.&lt;/strong&gt; With the Tech boom in Berlin comes a whole heap of physical offices. Even if you aren't technically inclined, these offices still have needs for general office duties. Receptionists assemble: &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://berlinstartupjobs.com"&gt;Berlin Startup Jobs&lt;/a&gt; is your best friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use your skills to Freelance.&lt;/strong&gt; Good with websites? Perhaps you're a budding copywriter. An artist or DJ? Freelance Visas aren't that hard to come by and if you can successfully build up a client base in Berlin you can live comfortably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="learn-german"&gt;Learn German&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can get a good grasp on the German language, you'll open up previously deadbolted doors. Telesales, shop assistants, retail, office jobs - you name it. You can cast a much larger net if you have at least conversational German language skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out a list of schools &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.mydestination.com/berlin/travel-articles/722695/top-10-language-schools-in-berlin"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="persist"&gt;Persist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all that said, it might seem like mission impossible to land a great job in Berlin. The truth is, it's quite tough, but I can't think of many better European capitals to be unemployed in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't give up. Persistance is the key to landing any job, and Berlin is no different. Make sure you have enough savings when you arrive so that you can live comfortably without a job for a couple of months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leave me a comment below with any tips or tricks you've got for finding work in Berlin!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to get a Working Holiday Visa in Germany - for Australians</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/working_visa_in_germany/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/working_visa_in_germany/</id>
    <published>2015-07-09T19:11:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-10T13:15:01+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a topic that springs up at least once a month when talking to other travelers and expats. Everybody seems to have a story on the best way to get a Working Holiday Visa. The truth is, there aren't any secrets or tricks - but in good old German fashion, you DO have to follow a particular method. Read on and I'll explain the necessary steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been living in Berlin since June 2014. I came here after spending 6 weeks in Portugal and a couple of weeks in London. The plan was to get my Working Holiday Visa, stick around for a year and then go home. I'm now in my 13th month (with a valid Visa, woohoo).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process I outline below comes from my own experience as an Australian national, but I know the process is identical for New Zealand and Chilean residents, and similar for Americans, Canadians and Japanese citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-easiest-but-not-necessarily-best-way-to-organise-a-working-holiday-visa"&gt;The easiest (but not necessarily best) way to organise a Working Holiday Visa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do it at home. This is the simplest way &lt;strong&gt;if you time it perfectly&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You fill in your &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.australien.diplo.de/contentblob/3975340/Daten/4777782/FormularDVisum.pdf"&gt;paperwork&lt;/a&gt;, make an appointment at the Consulate, submit your &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.australien.diplo.de/Vertretung/australien/en/Visa/Working-Holiday.html"&gt;documents&lt;/a&gt; and wait two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, but…if your Working Holiday Visa starts before the time you enter Germany, you are wasting time and money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-best-way-to-organise-a-working-holiday-visa"&gt;The best way to organise a Working Holiday Visa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right. Its quite a process, but fear not. Many have done it successfully before you, and I'm here to guide you through it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people get very nervous when they start applying for a Working Holiday Visa. This is one of the easiest German Visas to obtain. So don't stress, and remember:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Working Holiday Visa Programme is based on a bilateral agreement between the Federal Republic of Germany and Australia (also with New Zealand, Japan and Chile) and aims at enabling young Australian citizens to gain an insight into the culture and daily life of the Federal Republic of Germany, allowing them to travel to Germany for a stay of up to 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a mutual agreement between both countries. You have the right to apply and be there - regardless of how the woman on the other side of the counter is making you feel!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="step-minus-one-wait-three-months"&gt;Step Minus-One: Wait three months&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's right. Wait it out. Why? When you enter Germany, as an Australian you have 90 days as a tourist before you're obligated to leave (or get your Visa). What this means is that you can spend 15 glorious, legal months in old Deutschland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Downside:&lt;/strong&gt; You can't start work until you get your Visa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="step-one-register-an-address-in-germany"&gt;Step One: Register an address in Germany&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very first thing you should do is get to a &lt;strong&gt;Bürgerämt&lt;/strong&gt; and get your &lt;strong&gt;Anmeldung&lt;/strong&gt;. You have 14 days to do it, but I find they are lenient on that - still, Germany being Germany, do it ASAP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;Anmeldung&lt;/strong&gt; is the registration of you living at an address in Germany. A common misconception is that you must go to your local &lt;strong&gt;Bürgerämt&lt;/strong&gt;. This is not true. You may go to &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; office to register your address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Berlin, you can find a list of &lt;strong&gt;Bürgerämter&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://service.berlin.de/standorte/buergeraemter/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I would recommend making a booking online to avoid long waiting times, or getting there at least an hour before opening time to get an appointment for that day - even then, you may have to wait for a couple of hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring along your passport and your rental contract if you have one. If you are staying with friends, bring a translated letter saying you are staying at their house. If you are staying at a hotel/hostel, bring your booking confirmation (and produce it only if asked).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will get your &lt;strong&gt;Anmeldung&lt;/strong&gt; on the spot. This is free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your address is temporary, remember that when you move, you must complete this process again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="step-two-gather-your-documents"&gt;Step Two: Gather your documents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you have your &lt;strong&gt;Anmeldung&lt;/strong&gt;, the rest should be easy. You need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Valid passport&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 current biometric photo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;35mm x 45mm biometric passport photo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foreign travellers’ health insurance that is valid for one year&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proof of funds in the amount of at least 2,000 Euros e.g. bank statement&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the form “Antrag auf Erteilung eines Aufenthaltstitels" (Application for Issuance of a Residence Permit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="step-three-go-to-the-gates-of-hell"&gt;Step Three: Go to the Gates of Hell&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you've registered your address, collected your documents and you're ready to start work. Now all you need is the damn Visa. You're almost there! The problem however, is that you're not the only one who wants a Visa, and there's only one place you can get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's called the &lt;em&gt;Landesamt für Bürger- und Ordnungsangelegenheiten&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Ausländerbehörde&lt;/strong&gt; and it looks like something out of Nazi Germany (in Berlin anyway).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Ausländerbehörde" src="/images/auslandebehorde-84ef782b.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the same deal as the &lt;strong&gt;Bürgerämt&lt;/strong&gt; but with longer lines. Booking online is pretty much essential. You can probably even do it before you arrive, because the waiting list for appointments is long. The good news is that once you have that appointment, you are no longer tied to the 90 day tourist limit, so don't worry about making it before the cutoff if you've left it a little bit late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make an appointment in Berlin go &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://formular.berlin.de/xima-forms-29/nextpage/f2afb9c3-a3fa-4a68-9bdd-802d090edfa9/;jsessionid=F03AD6D614881368ADC616376E4F52F9"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="step-four-enter-the-gates-of-hell"&gt;Step Four: Enter the Gates of Hell&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's at this point that people really start to freak out. They've heard fairytales and they've heard nightmares. They frantically post in forums about the best tactics, tips and tricks. They try and drag their German-speaking friends along to help them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don't need to do any of that. Okay, nobody will speak to you in English. But if you've filled out your form correctly, have the rest of the documentation and are on time to your appointment, you'll be fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your number will flash up on the screen, just like in the deli, and tell you which room to go to. Walk down the hall and find the corresponding room. Knock, enter, find the desk and present your paperwork. Approximately three minutes later, s/he'll ask you for €50 - the website says &lt;em&gt;50 to 110 euros (depending on the effort)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; They may ask you how long you want it for. I've heard cases of people getting two years. Try your luck if they ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you pay (you'll need to go downstairs to pay with a card, try to bring cash) they'll send you back out to the waiting room while they process your Working Holiday Visa. This will take however long is left on your appointment (I suspect this isn't by mistake, they aren't exactly go-getters).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, your number will flash up on the deli-screen. This time, walk in with a big smile on your face and collect your passport. You won't collect $200 but you'll feel pretty good with the &lt;strong&gt;Ausländerbehörde&lt;/strong&gt; at your back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congrats, you can now work in Germany!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="step-five-congratulations-have-a-beer"&gt;Step Five: Congratulations! Have a beer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got walked out with my new Working Holiday Visa, I did the most stereotypical thing I could think of. I was living in Neukölln at the time, so I went to a Kebap shop on Hermannstr., ordered a Döner and a Sternburg and ate it in Tempelhofer Feld. This step isn't compulsory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, go forth and get yourself a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in Berlin? Berlin's unemployment rate is 10.8%, and there are plenty of people out there with EU passports who are willing to work for less than you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out my post on &lt;a href="/getting_a_job_in_berlin"&gt;Getting a Job in Berlin&lt;/a&gt; and leave me a comment below!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
