<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-07-18T20:32:00+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Fried Chicken in Berlin</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/fried_chicken_in_berlin/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/fried_chicken_in_berlin/</id>
    <published>2015-07-18T20:32:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-18T22:14:19+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fried chicken is one of my favourite foods, hands down. Since moving to Berlin, I've been on the hunt for the city's best. Fried chicken in a major city shouldn't be too hard to find, right? Wrong. So wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, you have the usual suspect: KFC. But that's not the fried chicken I'm talking about. I'm talking about golden, crispy, perfectly seasoned goodness housing moist, REAL chicken. Don't get me wrong - there's so many places to get amazing chicken, its just not in the style that I get a craving for every once in a while (usually a Sunday afternoon after a few too many Weißbiere).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In steps Risa Chicken. Their &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://chickenrisa.de/index.php/uber-uns"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; proclaims:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"Grillhähnchen auf echtem Holzkohlengrill-Immer frisch - immer knusprig - immer lecker". Grilled chicken on real wood charcoal grill - always fresh - always crispy - always delicious. I wasn't there for the grilled chicken though, I wanted the fried stuff!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Risa Chicken sits on the corner of Sonnenallee and Reuterstr in the heart of Neukölln (how the hell did I not know about this place when I lived 3 minutes away?). They also have Tempelhof and Moabit locations. I jumped on my bike and headed south across the canal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Risa Chicken" src="/images/risa-5b157351.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hopes were high as I parked my bike across the street. I could see the place was packed, but that wasn't going to stop me on my quest for BFC (Berlin Fried Chicken). Luckily, the queue wasn't too big when I got inside and I ordered 6 pieces of "Chicken Kross" and they told me it was going to be about 20 minutes. I asked for it take-away since the place was packed and I thought they might push it out faster, as some places do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked around the shop while I waited. There were pictures of Lebanon on the walls, so I'm hazarding a guess that's where the owner is from. In any case, Arabic was the main language being spoken - but the staff can speak German and English just fine, so it's tourist friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure enough, 10 minutes later my number was called and there were two take-away boxes sitting on the counter. I was under the impression that I was ordering tenderloins or similar. Alas, there were 6 huge breast portions. I jumped back on my bike and high tailed it to the flat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two boxes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Fried Chicken Boxes Berlin" src="/images/boxed_risa-de8f8873.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fried goodness:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Fried Chicken Berlin" src="/images/chicken-110e701d.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, Risa did not disappoint. OK, I've had better fried chicken in my lifetime, but it was pretty bloody good. Seasoning was great, chicken was still moist, even after the 15 minute ride home. Another point for the actual crispiness, you could hear the crunch in every bite unlike some other proprieters…looking at you, Colonel Sanders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd give this place a 4/5 stars. Staff were friendly enough, especially considering how busy it was. The chicken does exactly what it says on the tin: Fresh, crispy, delicious! If you're in the area, check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price:&lt;/strong&gt; 6 pieces of fried chicken breast: 7.09€ as of 18 July, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Sonnenallee 26, 12047 Berlin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class="embed-container"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m18!1m12!1m3!1d2429.598419444697!2d13.42879330000001!3d52.48640640000002!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x0000000000000000%3A0xa29d9224c6b4eefb!2sRIS+A+Chicken!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sde!4v1437250438670" width="600" height="450" frameborder="0" style="border:0" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A funny picture in oil and vinegar</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/funny_oil/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/funny_oil/</id>
    <published>2015-07-16T22:56:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-16T23:00:20+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My girlfriend poured olive oil and balsamic vinegar onto a plate to dip bread into. It looks like a cartoon duck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cartoon Duck" src="/images/oil-7a344239.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Chia Seed Pudding by a Superfood virgin!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/chia_seed_pudding/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/chia_seed_pudding/</id>
    <published>2015-07-14T21:04:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-15T13:33:46+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you might have assumed from the title, I'm not that conscious about what I eat. I love to eat out. In fact, eating out is one of my hobbies. I love to try new places, and I love to cook. Let's face it - a lot of great tasting food is unhealthy. I'm not here to tell you what you should be eating. That would make me a hypocrite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I saw an ad on Vimeo with Kelly Slater about Chia Pods, they mentioned that there was just three ingredients. Here's the video:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class="embed-container"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/119084184" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I did a little research of my own. (Allegedly) Chia seeds are a 'superfood' and are packed with a whole bunch of great stuff - fibre, omega-3, bla bla bla…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most days I skip breakfast. I know that's bad, but I'm lazy and I'm not a morning person. So when I saw a few videos of people making "Chia Pudding", I thought that it might just be the perfect breakfast to prepare the night before, whack in the fridge and take it to the office with me of a morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the recipes on YouTube and food blogs use a whole heap of ingredients. You can make these chia puddings so many ways. But they all work off the basis of adding liquid to chia. That's it. As you already know, I'm lazy when it comes to breakfast, so here's my version of a two ingredient chia pudding. I was doubtful that i'd like it but it was really good, and suprisingly filling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="chocolate-chia-pudding-recipe"&gt;Chocolate Chia Pudding Recipe&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Chia Pudding Recipe" src="/images/chia-ad972471.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="ingredients"&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chia Seeds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chocolate soy milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="method"&gt;Method&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put 2-3 tablespoons of chia seeds into a jar or cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add about a cup of chocolate soy milk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Chia Pudding Ingredients" src="/images/chia_ing-4316650d.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stir it all up (I actually put the lid on and shook it up).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put it in the fridge, and shake/stir it up about an hour later - you'll notice how much thicker it has become&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Chia Shake" src="/images/chiashake-9efbb1aa.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the fridge overnight&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy! Feel healthy. Boast about your new lifestyle. Instagram it #fitfam #cleanliving*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Chia Shake" src="/images/chia_finished-cc0fdfe8.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*I had a Cheeseburger for lunch 3 hours later 🙈🙊🙉&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cost of living in Berlin</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/cost_of_living_berlin/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/cost_of_living_berlin/</id>
    <published>2015-07-10T18:41:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-10T19:45:35+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Berlin is a relatively cheap city compared to other Euro-capitals. That said, its not what it used to be. It is the only city in Germany with a declining population, yet rent prices are on the rise due to an influx of expats like myself. Some locals (what's left of them) are understandably sour about being forced out of their beloved, poor-but-sexy Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="cost-of-accomodation-in-berlin"&gt;Cost of accomodation in Berlin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won't find a whole bunch of people buying houses in Berlin. It's a renter's game here and, of course, for an expat it makes sense to rent due to majority of us staying short-medium term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A shared flat in the city center will run you about 400€ warm/month (including utilities). Areas that were once much cheaper like Friedrichshain and Kreuzberg will now be on the upper end of that scale because of their proximity to nightlife, cafe's, galleries and the like. There are still bargains to be found in Neukölln, which is catching up fast to the other 'hipsterfied' areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a real bargain, get outside the S-Bahn ring. The commute to hotspots will be longer, but you'll be able to find a room for about 300€&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="S-Bahn" src="/images/ring-8a1f259c.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="cost-of-nightlife-in-berlin"&gt;Cost of nightlife in Berlin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clubs with a reputation will cost you between 15€ and 25€ just to get in. In general though, 5-8€ is a standard entry price. Bars are free to enter and often have live music. There are a lot of restaurants that get pretty vibey and you may end up staying there for a good chunk of your night after dinner for a few drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="cost-of-food-and-drinks-in-berlin"&gt;Cost of food and drinks in Berlin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this will depend on what you want to eat and drink, but I've found that drink prices is pretty standardized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4€ for a beer is on the expensive side. Most bars and clubs sit at about 3.50€ for a beer, and they will choose whether they want to add &lt;em&gt;Pfand&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Pfand&lt;/em&gt; is a deposit you pay on the glass when you buy your first drink. They'll give you a token in exchange for ~2€. When you finish your drink, you bring back your glass, return the token and get your money back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A half-liter of beer from a kiosk will set you back around 1€.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eating out in Berlin is very reasonable. Most mid-range restaurants will cost you about 8-10€ for a main, service included. There are super-expensive, Michelen starred restaurants too - expect to empty your wallet at these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast food is expensive in Berlin. You won't get away under 10€ at KFC for a meal-combo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A döner Kebap will cost you 3.50€ - beware, there are plenty of dodgy ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="cost-of-getting-around"&gt;Cost of getting around&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transport is fairly cheap in Berlin. A one way ticket that's valid for 2 hours in one direction will cost you 2.70€ in the AB zone. You can use the Bus, U-Bahn, S-Bahn, Tram and Ferry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you only need to go a short distance - defined as 3 U/S-Bahn stops or 6 Bus/Tram stops - opt for a 1.70€ Kurzstrecke (short-trip).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 7-Day pass will cost you 29.50€ for unlimited travel, a monthly 79.50€ and 700€ish for a yearly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxis start on 3.30€ and charge about 1.80€/km.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="cost-of-health-insurance"&gt;Cost of health insurance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Health insurance is compulsory. If you're on a &lt;a href="../working_visa_in_germany"&gt;Working Holiday Visa&lt;/a&gt;, travel insurance will be enough for legality. If you are living and working here though, you'll want to get some form of public/private insurance so you can visit the doctor or go to hospital if you need to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you're a freelancer, you'll need to get private health insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you work for a German based company, you can get public insurance which is subsidised. Your employer will deduct the health insurance payments from your salary - the amount is based on what you earn. You need to specify which company you want to be insured with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pay about 300€ a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="monthly-budget"&gt;Monthly Budget&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now this is going to significantly vary from person to person, but based on the above information here's a quick monthly budget if you couldn't be bothered reading the whole thing. This is from my own experience of living comfortably near the center of town, going out a few times a week and factoring in my insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class="table table-striped"&gt;
      &lt;thead&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Item&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Cost/month&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;/thead&gt;
      &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Rent&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;400€&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Weekly shop&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;160€&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Eating out two times a week&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;120€&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Bar/Club once a week &lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;160€&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Transport&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;80€&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Health Insurance&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;300€&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Total&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;1220€/month&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Renting a flat in Berlin</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/renting_a_flat_in_berlin/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/renting_a_flat_in_berlin/</id>
    <published>2015-07-10T15:54:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-10T17:08:20+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The idea of finding a place to live always fills me with mixed emotions. On the one hand there's the excitement of finding that great new flat. On the other hand you have to pack up all your stuff and lug it across town in the van you don't own. Then there's the competition. Oh, the competition. There will be lines…there &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be disappointment. But it will be worth it, because in Berlin, there is something out there for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at the below graphic. Pick two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pick Two" src="/images/picktwo-36d9b3ea.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can have a spacious, cheap apartment - but it won't be close to the action. You can get a cheap and central place, but you're going to have to share a studio. You get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; This is not gospel. There are plenty of exceptions to the rule. I know a guy that's still paying the same price he paid in the 90s for a 2 bedroom flat in Friedrichshain. I'd love to hear your stories in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-are-the-options"&gt;What are the options?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many different ways to go about getting a flat in Berlin. I'm going to list a few of the most common ones below and share my experience. Please, if you have anything to add, let me know!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="flatshare"&gt;Flatshare&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flatsharing in Berlin is one of the cheapest, easiest and most social ways to get accomodation. There are a heap of websites that you can search that display a whole heap of flatshares from short-term contracts to permanent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most ads will tell you the warm rent price, meaning bills are included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are a lot of flat shares in all areas of Berlin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The social aspect of moving in with new people&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flat shares are cheaper than living alone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your housemate/s may be f**king crazy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When one moves out, it becomes your responsibility to find another tenant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.wg-gesucht.de/en"&gt;http://www.wg-gesucht.de/en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/666822796665326"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/groups/666822796665326&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="get-your-own-place"&gt;Get your own place&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting your own rental contract is great. You have the freedom of living in your own house, making your own rules. If you want to leave the dishes out for a week at a time, you can (each to their own).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get your own contract, many landlords will want to see a SCHUFA credit check. You can get this online. They may also want proof of some of your last paychecks. If they choose you out of the &lt;strong&gt;many&lt;/strong&gt; people who walk through their flat, you'll have to give them a bond. This is usually 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They'll tell you the cold rent price. So make sure your budget allows for utilites. They may or may not include a kitchen in the price. Many tenants are expected to bring their own kitchen, so ask the question. You'll also need to furnish the place, so get ready to spend some serious money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The flat is yours - do what you want&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You're locked in for at least 12 months&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Privacy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It's expensive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The competition is fierce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unfurnished (most without kitchen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.wg-gesucht.de/en"&gt;http://www.wg-gesucht.de/en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.immobilienscout24.de/"&gt;http://www.immobilienscout24.de/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="airbnb"&gt;AirBnB&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I had determined my arrival date in Berlin, I also booked an AirBnB for 2 months. I figured two months would be enough time to explore the city and find out which area I wanted to move into long-term, along with the process it takes to get the flat in said area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AirBnB is great for a short term stay if you can find an affordable one. I chose a whole flat, told the host that I wanted it for two months and she knocked the price down for such a lengthy stay. In hindsight, this was actually the cheapest apartment we had (my housemate and I) at 700€ a month, including utilities and internet (and of course, it's furnished) in the heart of Neukölln.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Short term&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Furnished&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No bills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Short term&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It's going to be more expensive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.airbnb.com"&gt;http://www.airbnb.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="expat-rentals"&gt;Expat Rentals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was completely against expat rentals before coming to Berlin. In a strange twist of events, I now live in one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my AirBnB rental, I came across an expat rental company online and went to look at an apartment. It was big - really big, and it was a 9 minute tram to work in Mitte, a 15 minute walk down to Warschauer Str. and the bars in Friedrichshain. There were plenty of supermarkets nearby and there was one of the best parks in Berlin on our doorstep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was also furnished and all bills were included in the rental price of 900€ a month (between two of us). I could probably find a similarly sized house (2 bedroom, big kitchen, balcony) in the same street on my own contract for about 600€ a month - but I'd need to add utilities and internet on a monthly basis, and have a big initial layout for a kitchen, washing machine and all furniture. Who knew matresses were so damn expensive!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Short/medium/long-term&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Furnished&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bills included&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slightly more expensive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not that many apartments to choose from&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.xpatrentals.com/country/germany/berlin"&gt;https://www.xpatrentals.com/country/germany/berlin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.berlin99.com"&gt;http://www.berlin99.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.crocodilian.de/"&gt;https://www.crocodilian.de/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know how you got on with renting a place in Berlin. Are you renting at the same price you were when the Deutsche Mark was around? Let me know in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Getting a Job in Berlin</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/getting_a_job_in_berlin/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/getting_a_job_in_berlin/</id>
    <published>2015-07-10T11:18:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-10T13:21:39+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lets start by saying that this is no easy task. I overheard a conversation with two guys a while back - &lt;em&gt;Guy 1&lt;/em&gt; was a house-painter by trade. He was ready to work - would bring his van over from London, with all his brushes and rollers and make a life in Berlin. Simples. &lt;em&gt;Guy 2&lt;/em&gt; told him, in no uncertain terms, that for every one of him, there were 100 Polish house-painters who were willing to work longer, harder and for less money than he was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I don't know about Polish painters or their work ethic, but what I do know is that as an Australian in Berlin it's tough to find work. The figures speak for themselves. Currently unemployment in Berlin is at 10.8%. That's high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Unemployment in Berlin" src="/images/unemployment-67f97877.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="patience-is-a-virtue"&gt;Patience is a virtue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first piece of advice I can give you is to be patient. With unemployment so high, everybody is vying for the same jobs. You may not (I certainly hope you do!) fall into a job in the first week of getting your &lt;a href="../working_visa_in_germany/"&gt;Working Visa&lt;/a&gt;. It may even take a couple of &lt;em&gt;months&lt;/em&gt;. Be prepared. Bring enough money to survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="pick-the-right-industry"&gt;Pick the right industry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are jobs that are well suited to expats, travelers, backpackers and the like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm a 'Tech Professional', as it were. Berlin is the 'Silicon Valley of Europe' and so there were a lot of Tech positions in Startups that I had the opportunity of applying for. &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://berlinstartupjobs.com"&gt;Berlin Startup Jobs&lt;/a&gt; was a great resource for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are certain jobs that are really well suited to backpackers and travelers. They may not be what you do back at home, but if you're more about working to live in Berlin, then they might be perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tour Guide.&lt;/strong&gt; If you know a bit about history, look into running walking tours with a group like &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.neweuropetours.eu/work-with-us.html"&gt;Sandeman's&lt;/a&gt;. It's tip based, so you'll have good days and bad days, but from what I've worked out when participating on these tours - good days are very good. Summer is better, for obvious reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hostel Jobs.&lt;/strong&gt; This one is kind of obvious, but worth mentioning. Hostels are looking for expats to engage their customers. The job isnt glamourous - you'll clean toilets and make beds, but you might snag a free room, if you can hack living where you work. It also won't be very well paid, but you can survive Berlin on a budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bar Work.&lt;/strong&gt; This will be infinitely easier if you have a basic grasp of the German language, but there are plenty of bars and clubs around who will give you a job running glasses or mopping the floor. A lot of these places pay cash and the work may be sporadic - don't be disheartened if they let you go…it's not because you're shit at cleaning floors, when they can't afford you, they can't afford you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cafes/Restaurants.&lt;/strong&gt; There is an ever growing presence of English-speaking eateries in Berlin. A lot of these places don't cater to the German language whatsoever, so finding a job in an American burger joint for example, may be an option worth looking into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office Work.&lt;/strong&gt; With the Tech boom in Berlin comes a whole heap of physical offices. Even if you aren't technically inclined, these offices still have needs for general office duties. Receptionists assemble: &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://berlinstartupjobs.com"&gt;Berlin Startup Jobs&lt;/a&gt; is your best friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use your skills to Freelance.&lt;/strong&gt; Good with websites? Perhaps you're a budding copywriter. An artist or DJ? Freelance Visas aren't that hard to come by and if you can successfully build up a client base in Berlin you can live comfortably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="learn-german"&gt;Learn German&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can get a good grasp on the German language, you'll open up previously deadbolted doors. Telesales, shop assistants, retail, office jobs - you name it. You can cast a much larger net if you have at least conversational German language skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out a list of schools &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.mydestination.com/berlin/travel-articles/722695/top-10-language-schools-in-berlin"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="persist"&gt;Persist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all that said, it might seem like mission impossible to land a great job in Berlin. The truth is, it's quite tough, but I can't think of many better European capitals to be unemployed in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't give up. Persistance is the key to landing any job, and Berlin is no different. Make sure you have enough savings when you arrive so that you can live comfortably without a job for a couple of months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leave me a comment below with any tips or tricks you've got for finding work in Berlin!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
